when we think about running an economy
it requires year-over-year growth
requires it because your fractional
izing the monetary supply even deeper
than that just interest where the
monetary supply has to fundamentally
expand right then to not debase the
currency you have to increase the total
amount of goods and services services
sit on top of product economies which
relate to a linear materials economy
product materials economy which the
linear materials economy means
extracting resources from the planet
under nobley which means devastation of
ecosystems and things like that and then
turning them into trash in ways that
usually consume a good bit of energy
from dirty sources create a lot of
pollution and externalize harm to people
environments along the way you know and
then end with waste so that kind of
exponential growth economy and attached
to a linear materials economy just
doesn't work ongoingly on finite planet
right it only would work ongoingly on an
infinite playing field which were not on
and so that is a fundamentally self
terminating system it makes plenty of
sense that when there was just so much
low-hanging fruit in terms of coal and
oil and fish and trees and etc that we
would do this exponential boom kind of
thing it's just that's not viable
anymore it also happens to be that the
technology that would allow us to be
really viable in a post growth economic
system it's not about net more
consumption but about using the same
things in a closed-loop materials
economy in ever more interesting ways so
a materials economy that is closed-loop
post growth and upcycling continuously
upcycling the technology it takes to do
that is technology we are just now
getting happens to be that that's at the
same time that we are just now getting
to the point of self-determination of
the old system right so we both have to
shift and can at the same time